If you were already using a web tool
like claude or chatpt I think one of the
ones I would look at is typing mind
because it's same web type UI but it's
super configurable. You can create these
things called agents. It's a bit of an
overloaded term and in here it means
like a personality of an agent.
>> An agent is just something that can go
away and do something very autonomously
maybe even call out to sub aents. How
would you recommend to people [music]
to try and use an AI agent first?
[music]
Well, here's a very simple example that
I've used this one here called write
like Popey. [snorts] Now, all I've done
is in typing mind, I've updated a
knowledge base which is over here on the
left hand side. And in the knowledge
base, you can upload documents that uh
your agents in typing mind will have
access to. And so down here, I've got
one called Popey Blogs. And I've had a
blog since about 1997 or something.
[snorts] And I grabbed all the source
for all of the articles that I've ever
written and put them in here so that I
can have typing mind help me write an
article that sounds like I wrote it.
Now, I realize that sounds like I'm
just, you know, not ever going to write
any any blogs again because I'm just
going to leave it up to Typing Mind to
do it. But I did it as a test. I haven't
actually used it an awful lot. I've used
it a couple of times, but it's quite
remarkable that once it knows your style
of writing and your tone of voice and
the way that you write, uh, it's very,
um,
uh, able to create new content that
looks like you wrote it. It's it's quite
surprising. I can I can give you a
little demo. If I uh go back to the chat
and I say write like Popey, this has a
prompt in it that says write a blog
post, you know, the way Allan would
write. And down here, you can give it
access to those MCP servers that we'll
talk about a little bit more a bit
later. [snorts] But you can also give it
access to um the knowledge
[clears throat] base. And if I say, you
know, um, right, uh, right, I can't
type, write, uh, blog about new
developments,
MCP servers
in the command line.
So you the other thing you'll notice
while I'm while it's chugging away,
you'll see down here it says Claude
Sonet. Um, one of the nice thing about
uh, typing mind is you're not locked to
one of the providers. I could start a
chat and say actually I want to do this
with Gemini or I want to do this with
chat GPT and you can even fork
conversations partway through and change
from one model to another. So, this is
quite an advantage over just sitting in
the chat GPT web UI or the clawed web UI
because we're going to jump into the
second half of our conversation. But
first, a quick shout out to AI Native
DevCon. 2 days of hands-on sessions,
deep dives, and honest conversations
about what it means to build AI Native
software November 18th and 19th in New
York. Or join virtually from anywhere.
Tickets and details at a
native.io/devcon.
See you there. I I'm Claud don't give
you access to chat GBT and vice versa.
And so there's some interesting options
in here. Now you'll notice here it's
gone and found uh a blog post that I
wrote some time ago called command line
only laptop which is a ThinkPad that I
had a while ago. Um and then it like
reads a few more things, some other
articles that I've written. Um and down
here
I mean this is exactly the style of
content I would write. I'd put a TLDDR
at the top and then I'd write far too
many words and so it it's got that style
exactly right. Um and you know
subheadings like what on earth is MCP?
That kind of stuff. That's the style of
writing that I have. So the thing I like
about typing mind is it's doing a lot of
things all within one user interface.
It's able to connect to different uh
tools. It's able to uh have
[clears throat] knowledge uploaded to
it. uh not just blog posts like
documentation or existing code. Um and I
can access this from anywhere uh because
I I've signed up and I can access this
on my mobile phone and have a
conversation and actually start a
conversation and some software being
developed and then walk away and
continue somewhere else. One of the
other things that it has which is really
cool is one of the uh MCPs, one of the
tools that it has access to is called
file system. Now, this is handy because
I'm on a web page, but I can give this
tool access to specific directories on
my machine and say, write the code
directly on my machine. And that gets
away from what we used to do, which is
like have a conversation with an LLM and
copy and paste the code out of the
conversation. With this, it just goes
directly to that folder and we'll start
creating files. And when you go to that
folder, you'll see the the software we
created. And then later on I could use
the GitHub MCP to have it actually
create a repository on GitHub and upload
the whole thing and upload the readme
and even made the readme sound like me
and in the style of my other readme. So
it's I find this is a good um tool
typing mind a good agent for doing a lot
of different things in one place without
you having to switch between you know
all kinds of different uh tools and
utilities. And if you prefer the web UI
this is great for that.